[
  {
    "id": "45ba2bd2-60ac-4e7b-af0c-87fba099832a",
    "question": "What is a correct syntax to output \"Hello World\" in Python?",
    "options": [
      "print(\"Hello World\")",
      "echo(\"Hello World\");",
      "echo \"Hello World\"",
      "p(\"Hello World\")"
    ],
    "correct": "print(\"Hello World\")"
  },
  {
    "id": "02cea70e-41b1-45b4-bf9f-a9d4c726c3bc",
    "question": "How do you insert COMMENTS in Python code?",
    "options": [
      "#This is a comment",
      "/*This is a comment*/",
      "//This is a comment"
    ],
    "correct": "#This is a comment"
  },
  {
    "id": "d4d11da8-d0f0-4401-ae6a-a3239dc3512c",
    "question": "Which one is NOT a legal variable name?",
    "options": [
      "my-var",
      "my_var",
      "_myvar",
      "Myvar"
    ],
    "correct": "my-var"
  },
  {
    "id": "a1136536-859a-4184-a2d7-d4872bcdae69",
    "question": "How do you create a variable with the numeric value 5?",
    "options": [
      "Both the other answers are correct",
      "x = 5",
      "x = int(5)"
    ],
    "correct": "Both the other answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "id": "705bc55c-f04f-4e46-b52f-3bb2c7e89a36",
    "question": "What is the correct file extension for Python files?",
    "options": [
      ".py",
      ".pyth",
      ".pt",
      ".pyt"
    ],
    "correct": ".py"
  },
  {
    "id": "9413f678-d62d-4b1c-b7ec-d3f9e75da071",
    "question": "How do you create a variable with the floating number 2.8?",
    "options": [
      "Both the other answers are correct",
      "x = 2.8",
      "x = float(2.8)"
    ],
    "correct": "Both the other answers are correct"
  },
  {
    "id": "10bd1f9d-ed94-41d8-b397-9140f88f8cb1",
    "question": "What is the correct syntax to output the type of a variable or object in Python?",
    "options": [
      "print(type(x))",
      "print(typeOf(x))",
      "print(typeof(x))",
      "print(typeof x)"
    ],
    "correct": "print(type(x))"
  },
  {
    "id": "2fd9c1ed-3557-46ce-8be5-d0fae2846120",
    "question": "What is the correct way to create a function in Python?",
    "options": [
      "def myFunction():",
      "function myfunction():",
      "create myFunction():"
    ],
    "correct": "def myFunction():"
  },
  {
    "id": "4f0571bd-6481-4eed-b470-d33e4f6c20a4",
    "question": "In Python, 'Hello', is the same as \"Hello\"",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "id": "8aae4de5-68f4-437c-adc2-f3dfbdc45196",
    "question": "What is a correct syntax to return the first character in a string?",
    "options": [
      "x = \"Hello\"[0]",
      "x = \"Hello\".sub(0, 1)",
      "x = sub(\"Hello\", 0, 1)"
    ],
    "correct": "x = \"Hello\"[0]"
  },
  {
    "id": "0a9d251a-c4c1-48b9-a17f-cb3bb092601e",
    "question": "Which method can be used to remove any whitespace from both the beginning and the end of a string?",
    "options": [
      "strip()",
      "len()",
      "ptrim()",
      "trim()"
    ],
    "correct": "strip()"
  },
  {
    "id": "356be48c-e552-4ef3-aac0-3c5cec74614e",
    "question": "Which method can be used to return a string in upper case letters?",
    "options": [
      "upper()",
      "upperCase()",
      "toUpperCase()",
      "uppercase()"
    ],
    "correct": "upper()"
  },
  {
    "id": "666ffca3-37af-4a5d-9aac-55c7941f4fd5",
    "question": "Which method can be used to replace parts of a string?",
    "options": [
      "replace()",
      "replaceString()",
      "switch()",
      "repl()"
    ],
    "correct": "replace()"
  },
  {
    "id": "2e55e829-7f39-4044-b7c4-a34e693c803b",
    "question": "Which operator is used to multiply numbers?",
    "options": [
      "*",
      "%",
      "#",
      "x"
    ],
    "correct": "*"
  },
  {
    "id": "939e0c47-3e2d-4277-9e39-bdb4cd0cd83f",
    "question": "Which operator can be used to compare two values?",
    "options": [
      "==",
      "><",
      "<>",
      "="
    ],
    "correct": "=="
  },
  {
    "id": "78c0f0a3-f5c1-41d4-af85-a3eca258b015",
    "question": "Which of these collections defines a LIST?",
    "options": [
      "[\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"]",
      "{\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"}",
      "(\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\")",
      "{\"name\": \"apple\", \"color\": \"green\"}"
    ],
    "correct": "[\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"]"
  },
  {
    "id": "bb749a26-182c-47e1-bb39-4af0da9bacb3",
    "question": "Which of these collections defines a TUPLE?",
    "options": [
      "(\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\")",
      "{\"name\": \"apple\", \"color\": \"green\"}",
      "{\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"}",
      "[\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"]"
    ],
    "correct": "(\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\")"
  },
  {
    "id": "e08c7354-7922-49ab-a313-419d5856355d",
    "question": "Which of these collections defines a SET?",
    "options": [
      "{\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"}",
      "(\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\")",
      "[\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"]",
      "{\"name\": \"apple\", \"color\": \"green\"}"
    ],
    "correct": "{\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"}"
  },
  {
    "id": "dcee70c0-9b1e-4acc-a093-03b8adf71082",
    "question": "Which of these collections defines a DICTIONARY?",
    "options": [
      "{\"name\": \"apple\", \"color\": \"green\"}",
      "(\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\")",
      "[\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"]",
      "{\"apple\", \"banana\", \"cherry\"}"
    ],
    "correct": "{\"name\": \"apple\", \"color\": \"green\"}"
  },
  {
    "id": "78336aba-6cfa-4622-8a68-6fb55759eaba",
    "question": "Which collection is ordered, changeable, and allows duplicate members?",
    "options": [
      "LIST",
      "SET",
      "TUPLE",
      "DICTIONARY"
    ],
    "correct": "LIST"
  },
  {
    "id": "90407883-c811-4097-ac36-2b2470c957b1",
    "question": "Which collection does not allow duplicate members?",
    "options": [
      "SET",
      "TUPLE",
      "LIST"
    ],
    "correct": "SET"
  },
  {
    "id": "860661e2-cd20-4f1c-b01e-a7fa2caaae42",
    "question": "How do you start writing an if statement in Python?",
    "options": [
      "if x > y:",
      "if (x > y)",
      "if x > y then:"
    ],
    "correct": "if x > y:"
  },
  {
    "id": "6404db36-4ddd-44aa-a125-395042f472a5",
    "question": "How do you start writing a while loop in Python?",
    "options": [
      "while x > y:",
      "x > y while {",
      "while x > y {",
      "while (x > y)"
    ],
    "correct": "while x > y:"
  },
  {
    "id": "5af2ae04-1f23-4d78-bb56-d9e276e81ed4",
    "question": "How do you start writing a for loop in Python?",
    "options": [
      "for x in y:",
      "for x > y:",
      "for each x in y:"
    ],
    "correct": "for x in y:"
  },
  {
    "id": "7c18d73d-b7ba-42e4-b4cb-396d34c943d7",
    "question": "Which statement is used to stop a loop?",
    "options": [
      "break",
      "exit",
      "stop",
      "return"
    ],
    "correct": "break"
  }
]